

# **MOHIT KOTHARI**

mohitkothari6@gmail.com | +91 720 406 8948

Chennai, TN 600017

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Strategic-minded, goal-driven account manager with over six years of verifiable successes in sales across food-tech, design, retail and Food and Beverage industry. Exceptional ability to build and lead high-performing teams focused on developing profitable sales strategies and identifying market opportunities to achieve sales goals. An adaptable, customerfocused leader with a proven track record of bringing revenues, profits, and market shares to new heights.

## SKILLS

- Salesforce
- Adobe Photoshop
- Microsoft Office

- Bartending
- Sales
- Account Management

## **WORK HISTORY**

**Restaurant Manager** | Kommune Restobar - Chennai, Tamil Nadu

04/2018 - CURRENT

- Manage the business aspects of the bar, such as keeping a current liquor license, negotiating supplier contracts, taking inventory and reordering supplies, managing budgets, and setting goals.
- Hiring and training staff to provide excellent service to patrons.
- Creating effective schedules and quickly resolving conflicts to ensure that the bar is well staffed during peak hours.
- Setting and enforcing quality and safety controls.
- Ensuring licenses are updated and in line with current legislation.
- Working with diverse personalities both on the staff and patrons.
- Planning and taking part in promotional events.
- Diffusing tense situations between patrons or staff members to prevent possible safety or legal issues, ejecting unruly persons, if needed.
- Maintaining a fun, safe atmosphere for patrons.

**Senior Territory Sales Manager** | Practo - Chennai, 01/2018 - 03/2018 Tamil Nadu

- Meet prospective clients, execute effective product demonstrations, emphasizing product features and benefits with focus on the value of the solution.
- Consult with physician practices to understand practice workflow needs and expectations.
- Prospect, educate, qualify, and generate interest for Sales

- Opportunities.
- Develop and accomplish a lead generation plan including Outbound and Inbound prospect management.
- Follow up with prospective clients and should be an expert in closing deals.
- Attending sales group meetings concerning sales targets, forecasts, and reporting on market situation and competition.
- Participating in conferences, representing the company for brand awareness.
- Maintaining and expanding the database of prospects for the organization.
- Providing suggestions to improvise on sales and marketing strategies.

## Sales Manager | Arvind & Co - Chennai, Tamil Nadu 01/2017 - 12/2017

- Confer with sales and management executives or with clients in order to discuss design ideas.
- Provide sample garments to agents and sales representatives, and arrange for showings of sample garments at sales meetings or fashion shows.
- Determine prices for styles.
- Visit textile showrooms to keep up-to-date on the latest fabrics.
- Confer with coworkers to obtain information about orders, processes, or problems.

## **Business Development Lead** | Houzify - Bengaluru, 10/2015 - 12/2016 Karnataka

- Was one of the founding members of the company and headed sales, partnerships across India.
- Involved in hiring, cross functional learning as well as product development.
- Confer with client to determine factors affecting planning interior environments, such as budget, architectural preferences, and purpose and function.
- Coordinate with other professionals, such as contractors, architects, engineers, and plumbers, to ensure job success for a specified lead
- Estimate material requirements and costs, and present design to client for approval.
- Use computer-aided drafting (CAD) and related software to produce construction documents.

## Sales & Marketing Manager | Zomato - Bengaluru, 04/2014 - 10/2015 Karnataka

 Help restaurants market themselves better by selling advertising space.

- Manage end-to-end client relationship including pitching, negotiation, contracting, billing / invoicing, payment collection, graphic design support (with the help of the Graphics Team), campaign activations, result tracking and troubleshooting.
- Handled accounts of more than 60 restaurants across the city ranging from takeaway restaurants to five star hotels and billing valuing to ~\$15,000 on a monthly basis.
- April'13 June'13 TRAVELGURU BENGALURU, INDIA.

## Intern | Yatra.com - Bengaluru, Karnataka

04/2013 - 06/2013

- Primary responsibility included meeting hotel owners across different cities and get them on board for the platform by negotiation travel agent commission.
- Managed to bag 150 hotels in two month across Bengaluru, Chennai & Hyderabad.
- Community Feb 2017 TALKING EARTH CHENNAI, INDIA Mapping Volunteer/ Fundraiser Talking Earth mobilizes communities to take control of their urban ecosystems by providing them with the tools, information, and platforms to protect the environment.
- This data helps to monitor climate change at a micro/ macro level.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Christ University, Bengaluru

05/2014

#### **BBA**: Business Administration

- Authored research papers titled, a) A study on consumer perception regarding Private label Branding in India [published in the European journal of Business & Management] b) Impact of WOM on traditional shopping methods Vs online methods in the electronic appliance industry.
- Organized TEDx Christ University in 2012 & 2013.
- Certified in basic French, Bartending, Print Journalism.